好了  吊灯降下来
Okay, cue the chandelier.
伊利诺伊州  那离曼哈顿十万八千里啊
Illinois? That's like 500 miles from Manhattan.
不  我知道西北大学比斯坦福大学近一点
No, I know Northwestern is closer than Stanford.
我的意思是
I'm just saying,
-那不是你想去的地方  -阿丽克西斯
- that's not where you want to go. - Alexis?
等等  阿什  我爸在跟我说话  干啥
Hold on, Ash. My dad's talking to me. What?
-今天没课吗  -有
- Don't you have school? - Yes.
听我说  阿什  我了解你
Look, Ash, I know you,
我觉得你该离家独立了
and I think you need to get away from home.
-我是说  我们都该离家独立了  -说啥呢
- I mean, we all need to get away from home. - Hey.
我得挂了  回头再说
I gotta go. We'll talk about this later.
我也爱你  拜拜
Love you, too. Bye.
居然说"我们都该离家独立了"
"We all need to get away from home"?
不  我永远都不离开
No. I should never leave.
我们可以上演父女版的《灰色花园》了
We can be the father-daughter version of "Grey Gardens."
你看起来好像没怎么睡啊
You look like you didn't get any sleep.
是没睡
I didn't.
阿什利接到了大学录取通知书
I mean, Ashley got his college acceptances.
他差不多哪都能去
He got in everywhere.
好啊  不好吗
Well, that's great. That's not great?
我查看了关于高中恋人的统计数据
I looked up statistics for high-school sweethearts
当其中一个去外州上大学
when one of them goes to college out of state
另一个还留在高中上学时
and the other stays in high school.
分手的概率相当高
The odds are not in our favor.
我是说  我希望他去他想去的学校
I mean, I want him to go where he wants,
但我又不想他走  他也不想走
But I don't want him to leave, and he doesn't want to leave,
但我又不希望他因为没去成梦想中的学校而恨我
But I don't want him to resent me for not going where he wants,
我真不知道该怎么办好
and I don't know what to do.
跟我学呗  概率虽小  并不代表成功无望啊
Well, do what I do. Look at the odds as a challenge.
你去赌城逢赌必输  还有脸说这话
Says the man who always loses in Vegas.
维持一段感情确是难事
Relationships are hard.
但通常来说  都会有解决之道
Odds are, you'll figure it out.
通常来说  该是又有命案了
Odds are, someone's dead.
卡塞尔
Castle.
开什么玩笑呢
You've gotta be kidding me.
在维拜塔酒店发生了谋杀案
A murder in the theater of the V.B. Tower Hotel,
在维克多·拜伦的地盘上
Victor Baron's place?
死者不会正是他吧
It's not the Baron, is it?
不是  但你不会失望的
No, but you won't be disappointed.
-这个案子正合你口味呢  -何出此言
- This one's right up your alley. - Why is that?
因为被害人是位选手
Because our victim is a contestant.
选美皇后之死  听着就有猫腻啊
Death of a beauty queen, scandalous.
是啊  怎么不发生的更频繁点啊
Yeah, surprised it doesn't happen more often.
那位莫非是美国老爸  鲍比·斯塔克
Is that America's dad, Bobby Stark?
他在这干嘛
What's he doing here?
他是选美大赛的主持人
He's the pageant host.
别跟我说你是他情景喜剧的观众啊
Oh, please don't tell me that you watch his sitcom.
《家族怪癖》吗
"Family Foibles"?
我为人父的理论知识
Half of what I know about being a father,
一半都是从那个剧看来的
I learned from watching that show.
-嘿  贝克特  -说说事情经过
- Hey, Beckett. - So what's the story?
据选美负责人坎迪丝·弗德讲
Well, according to Candace Ford, our pageant manager,
死者是21岁的安波儿·米德伯瑞
the victim is 21-year-old Amber Middleberry.
选手们在彩排一个众演剧目
The contestants were rehearsing a production number.
他们把灯架降下来的时候
When they brought in the lighting truss,
安波儿就绑在上面
Amber was tangled up inside of it.
-彩排被迫因此中止  -帕穆特  你好啊
- Must've been a showstopper. - Hey there, Perlmutter.
-探长  作家  -死因是什么
- Detective. Writer. - Cause of death?
从背后被人用她自己的肩带勒死
Choked from behind with her own sash,
死亡时间约在夜里十一点到凌晨一点间
Probably between 11:00 p.m. and 1:00 a.m.
她怎么跑到灯架上的
How did she end up on the lighting truss?
据我们推断  昨天的彩排之后
Near as we can tell, the, uh, lighting truss
灯架就留在台上了
was left on stage after yesterday's rehearsal.
凶手大概觉得把她扔在这上面
Killer probably thought he'd buy some time
升上去  可以让尸体迟一点被发现
by dumping her on it and raising it up to the rafters.
那么凶手必须会使用舞台设备才行
So whoever it was must have known how to use the stage equipment.
不一定  升降控制是触屏的
Nah, the lift controls, they're on a touch screen.
挺好操作的
Pretty easy to operate.
-生前最后一次露面是什么时候  -昨晚
- When was she last seen alive? - Last night.
所有选手都去参加向维克多·拜伦致敬的晚宴
Contestants, they all went to a dinner to honor Victor Baron.
十点半的时候  派对结束
10:30, the party wrapped,
他们都乘豪华轿车回到酒店
and they were all limoed back here to the hotel.
安波儿在10:43时使用过房卡进入自己的房间
Amber used her key card at 10:43 p.m. to get into her hotel room.
之后就跑到这来了
After that, she, uh, wound up here.
探长  你该看看这个
Detective, there's something you should see.
黑色小亮片
A black sequin?
是亮片的一部分  她头发里发现的
Part of one. I found it in her hair.
好的  可能是凶手勒死她的时候
Okay, so the killer might have transferred it
落在她身上了
when he strangled her.
我们去查查昨晚都谁能进这个舞厅
Let's find out who had access to this ballroom last night.
再跟选美负责人谈谈
And let's also talk to the pageant manager.
查查看有没有哪个女孩的服装
I want to see if any of the girls' outfits
-能跟这个亮片匹配上  -好的
- match with this sequin. - Will do.
安波儿·米德伯瑞有亲人吗
So does Amber Middleberry have any family?
有  只有  她爸爸
Yeah. Just her, uh, dad.
她从九岁开始选美
She started when she was 9...
"小童星"选美大赛
Little Miss Wholesome.
一开始我很反对的
Oh, I was against the whole idea at first,
但是安波儿的妈妈却非常热衷于此
but Amber's mom had a bug about it, and, uh,
她妈妈去世后
and after her mother died...
我想选美可以抚慰她对母亲的思念
I think it just helped her feel closer to her.
你知道你女儿有什么仇人吗
Did your daughter have any enemies that you know of?
没有  当然没有  大家都很喜欢安波儿
No, of course not. Everybody loved Amber.
那其他的选手呢
Well, what about the other contestants?
有竞争对手吗
Were there any rivalries?
她跟这里的一些女孩子交情很深的
She went way back with some of these girls.
她们  甚至在她进入半决赛后
They, even after she made it to the semifinals,
大家都来拥抱她  她们都...
everybody was hugging her, and they were...
她们都说她是"先锋美后'呢
they were calling her the front-runner, and, uh...
选美  赢得本次选美  是她的梦想
This pageant, this one... was her dream.
你最后一次和她说话是什么时候
When was the last time you talked with her?
昨天早上  我昨晚想给她打电话来着
Yesterday morning. I, uh, I tried to call her last night.
我知道晚宴结束了
I knew that dinner thing was over.
想祝她好运
I wanted to wish her luck, you know,
她却没接电话
but... she didn't answer the phone.
那是什么时候的事
And what time was that?
11点不到
A little before 11:00.
我以为她一定是睡了
I, uh... I thought she must have gone to sleep,
但她肯定是离开她的房间
but she must have left her room
不知为什么跑到这来了
and come down here for some reason.
Dan
Dan.
我真难过
I am so sorry.
我们一定会抓到丧尽天良的凶手
We're gonna get the bastard who did this.
-我保证  -谢谢你  拜伦先生
- You have my word. - Thank you, Mr. Baron.
探长  不介意的话  我们楼上说话
Detectives, a word upstairs if you don't mind.
今天是沉痛的一天
This is a dark day.
拜伦全美选美大赛历史上悲痛的一页
A sad chapter in the history of Baron's All-American Beauty Pageant.
维克多  真是太可怕了
Victor, this is just awful.
内人凯拉
My wife Kayla.
你们或许也认识她
You might recognize her
-95年摘得拜伦全美小姐桂冠  -久闻了
- as Baron's All-American Beauty, 1995. - Yes, of course.
见到你很高兴
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, yes.
这真是令人心碎  对我们  对其他女孩都是的
This is just devastating, for us and... and for the girls.
我们就像一家人
We... we're like family.
你们有多了解她
How well did you know her?
她是个很甜美的女孩  出色的小提琴手
Um, sh-she was a sweet girl, a hell of a violinist.
是的
Yes, she was.
请记住我说的  我将倾尽拜伦帝国全部的力量
Mark my words--I am putting the entire weight
来支持此次调查
of the Baron empire behind this investigation.
任何需要  尽管开口
Anything you need, just say the word.
探长  我知道  你必须秉公执法
Detective, I know, uh, you have to do your thing.
我只是希望
Uh, I'm just hoping,
因为本周五我们将会直播本次选美
Uh, since we are airing the pageant live this Friday,
如果能减少媒体曝光度  你明白的
if we could minimize the press, you know,
对其他女孩们公平一些
to be fair to the other girls.
我们会先为受害人寻求公平
We're gonna have to be fair to our victim first.
说到媒体  可以把摄像头都关了吗
And speaking of press, could we get rid of the cameras?
这  毕竟是一起谋杀案的调查
This is, after all, a murder investigation,
而不是真人秀
not a reality show.
我们  我们录下选美幕后
We, um, we film everything...
所有的场景
behind the scenes at the pageant.
我们希望捕捉到女孩们对彼此的看法
We like to catch the girls talking about each other,
让她们畅谈心中的希望和恐惧
let them confess their hopes and fears.
明星光环头顶绕  幕后斗争不能少
You get the glamour, but you also get the underbelly.
-观众们最爱看幕后"花絮"了  -没错
- People love the underbelly. - Yes, they do.
或许现在该停止拍摄才对
But maybe this isn't the time.
那么所有的女孩都住在酒店吗
So were all the girls staying at the hotel?
-是这样的  -好的  我需要去安波儿的房间看看
- That's right. - Okay, I'll need access to Amber's room.
我们还需要酒店的监控录像带
We'll also need hotel security tapes.
那些摄像机都录下昨天的晚宴了吗
Now were those cameras recording last night's dinner?
当然
Of course.
我们需要录影带
Okay, we'll need the footage.
还需要询问本次选美的所有参赛者
We'll also need to interview all of the pageant contestants.
我会让坎迪丝满足你们的一切所需
I'll have Candace give you anything you need.
很好  非常感谢您
Great. Thank you very much.
-很高兴见到你  -欢迎下次再来
- It was nice to meet you. - Come again.
不  我们不要
Oh, no, we don't--
我们不想他们再来了
We don't want them to come again.
小镇姑娘为了童话故事来到纽约
Small-town girl comes to New York for the fairy tale,
却以恐怖故事结尾
ends up with the horror story.
选美不是童话故事
Pageants aren't fairy tales.
而是一项高要求  高压力的比赛
They're demanding, high-pressure competitions
将人性中最闪亮的和最黑暗的特质都发掘出来
that bring out the very best and the very worst in people.
听起来真是经验之谈啊
That is the voice of experience.
我的天  你是选美皇后
Oh, my god. You were a beauty queen.
不是  大一时我有个舍友叫黛比·文妮科
No. I had a roommate freshman year--Debbie Winokur.
就像是和服用类固醇的艾丽·伍兹生活在一起
It was like living with Elle Woods on steroids.
那么...
Well, then...
这场景应该会唤起不少回忆吧
This ought to bring back some memories.
你太没精打采了  冠军永远不会没精打采的
You're slouching. Winners never slouch.
卡塞尔  到处都是
Castle, they're everywhere.
闻起来就像百货公司里的香水柜台
Smells like a perfume counter at a department store.
比平常办案遇到的无赖疯子等劲爆多了
Beats the usual lowlifes and nut jobs.
不知道你是否可以改正偏见
I don't know if you can say
疯子和选美皇后是完全不搭边的
that nut jobs and beauty queens are mutually exclusive.
是的  但是她们都与谋杀案无关
Yeah, but none of 'em connect to the murder.
我检查了她们衣服上的小亮片
I checked the sequin against all their dresses...
趁机揩油了吧
I bet you did.
没有相匹配的
And none of 'em are a match.
好吧  看一下晚宴的录像
Okay, look at the footage from the dinner.
确认一下  我们检查的衣服
Let's make sure that the dresses we checked
确实是她们昨天穿的
are the ones they actually wore.
观看美女们穿着晚礼服走动吗
Watch a parade of beautiful women in evening attire?
好  交给我吧
Yeah, I can do that.
那是当然
I bet you can.
嘿  我将这些女孩们都询问了一遍
Hey, so I've been interviewing these ladies...
那是当然
I bet you did.
有关她们昨晚的不在场证明
About their alibis last night.
总之  有个人你们应该去和她谈谈
Anyway, there's someone that you should talk to.
告诉他们
so tell 'em
你刚刚告诉我的晚宴后发生的事情
what you told me about what happened after dinner.
当我们回到酒店
When we got back to the hotel,
我想要练习一组舞蹈动作
I wanted to go work out a couple of my dance moves.
我是半决赛选手之一  所以我在节目中有表演项目
I'm one of the semifinalists, so I get to perform in the broadcast.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
谢谢  我准备用舞蹈诠释
Thanks. I'm doing an interpretive dance
詹妮弗·洛佩慈的歌曲《我喜欢你》
to Jlo's "I'm into you."
然后发生了什么
And then what happened?
我换了运动服  来到了舞台
I changed into sweats and went to the stage,
然后我就听到了
and that's when I heard it.
听到什么了
You heard what?
吵架
Uh, a fight.
是从更衣室传来的
It was coming from the dressing room.
是安波儿和一个男人
It was Amber and some guy.
-你看到是谁了吗  -门是关着的
- Did you see the guy? - The door was closed.
声音越来越大  所以我就锁了门
It started getting loud, so I bolted.
但现在我希望我当时能做点什么
But now I wish I had done something.
也许他就是杀她的凶手
I mean... Maybe he's the one who killed her.
他的声音  你能听出是谁吗
His voice, did you recognize it?
不能
No.
他们在吵什么
What were they arguing about?
"你怎么可以这样对我  你没权力
"How could you do this to me? You have no right.
你以为你是谁"  这一类的
Who do you think you are?" Stuff like that.
听起来他有点像是她男朋友
It kinda sounded like he was her boyfriend.
刚刚是安波儿的爸爸
So that was Amber's dad.
他说他不知道女儿有交男朋友
He said he didn't know anything about a boyfriend.
其他女孩也表示不知情
Neither did any of the other girls.
也许她进行的是地下恋情
Maybe she was keeping it a secret.
他说  只有一个人知道安波儿的私生活情况
He said, if anyone knew what was going on in Amber's life,
就是贾斯汀·汉克尔 安波儿的选美顾问
it was, uh, Justin Hankel, Amber's pageant consultant.
我安排她的日常生活  采访
I coached her on her routine, interviews,
监督她的造型  化妆  衣服  小提琴课
oversaw stylists, makeup, clothing, violin lessons,
魅力展示  赢得比赛所需的一切努力
glamour shots-- everything she needed to win.
你们俩一定有很多时间在一起
The two of you must have spent a lot of time together.
那是必须的
Well, that's what it takes.
现在的选美不仅仅是漂亮就行的
Today's pageants are not just about beauty.
更关乎头脑  才艺  社交能力
They're about brains, talent, social issues.
一旦当选  奖金和媒体曝光度  实在诱惑
and what, with the money and the exposure at stake,
赢得任意一项就可以开启成功的事业
Winning one of the majors can launch a career.
那男朋友呢  她恋爱了吗
What about a boyfriend? Was she in a relationship?
没有男朋友  这是我对客户的要求之一
No boyfriends. That is a rule for my clients,
安波儿也不例外
And Amber was no exception.
她知道她必须要把精力全部用在选美上
She knew that she needed to focus 100% of her energy on the pageant.
你知道吗  她死的那晚  和别人吵了一架
You know, the night that she died, she got into an argument.
知道和谁吗
Any idea with who?
不  我最后见到她是在晚宴前
No. The last time I saw her was before her dinner.
但是正如我对另外那名警官所说
But like I told that other detective,
肯定有什么事
something was going on.
何出此言
How so?
她最近几天都不在状态  心烦意乱
She'd been off the last couple of days, upset.
我接她去试衣服的时候
And I went to pick her up for a costume fitting,
她看起来好像刚刚哭过
and it looked like she had been crying.
你有没有问她为什么
Did you ask why?
她说有人想占她便宜
She said that someone was trying to take advantage of her.
我问了是谁  但是她说她会处理好的
I asked her who, but she said she would handle it.
不对我说实话  这点不像她
It j--it wasn't like her not to confide in me.
会不会是其他的参赛者
Could it have been one of the other contestants?
这些女孩为了赢得比赛都承受着巨大压力
There's a lot of pressure on these girls to win.
她们之间的关系也很阴暗复杂
And it can get really... "political" between them.
阴暗复杂的关系有没有可能最终让她丧命呢
Do you think it's possible political turned deadly?
我不知道  夺冠意味着获得名声和财富
I don't know. Winning means fame and fortune.
没人会关注第二名
No one remembers the runner-up.
再说了  比这更弱的动机都能让人萌生杀机
Besides, people have killed for less.
那还是没法解释她和谁吵架
That still doesn't explain who she was arguing with.
伙计们  我有线索了
Guys. I got something.
是其中一个女孩吗
One of the girls?
-先看着  -我还是小女孩的时候
- Just watch. Ever since I was a little girl...
这是昨晚拜伦晚宴的录像
This is from Baron's dinner last night.
那是我们的被害人安波儿
That's our victim, Amber.
我很荣幸能来到这里
And I just feel so very honored to be here.
她在拍维克多·拜伦的马屁
She's laying it on thick for Victor Baron.
但是  那还不是最有意思的部分
But that's not the interesting part.
再看看这个
Now watch this.
这里
Ah. There.
看到了吗
See that?
看她的脸
Look at her face.
看起来不论情景喜剧之星鲍比·斯塔克说了什么
Looks like whatever good-guy sitcom star Bobby Stark said,
她都不喜欢
she didn't like it.
别光看她的脸
Don't just look at her face.
看看他的晚礼服
Look at his tux.
黑色小亮片
Black sequins.
翻译：千花  旺妹  媛媛  DJ  LyraL  米苏  落末一地
时间轴：小穗    校对：大卫熊   Ethan-泽生   后期&总监：瓜瓜
鲍比·斯塔克的礼服
Bobby Stark's blazer,
多亏了选美大赛的服装师
courtesy of the costume lady at the pageant.
-毁坏的黑色亮片呢  -完全吻合
-And the broken black sequin? - Perfect match.
服装师爆粗  弄坏衣服  真是混蛋
Bam, said the costume lady.
她不是唯一一个提到鲍比·斯塔克时
Ooh, she's not the only lady saying bam
-骂脏话的  -他有前科吗
- When it comes to Bobby Stark. - Does he have a record?
没有刑事指控
Uh, no criminal charges,
但斯塔克名声相当不好
But Mr. Stark has quite the reputation.
去年有三名女子申请了对他的限制令
Three women filed restraining orders against Bobby Stark in the last year
理由都是骚扰挑逗
all for unwanted advances.
怎么名人八卦网上没这消息
How come I didn't hear about this on "TMZ"?
据说斯塔克付了
Oh, word is Stark paid
一大笔钱封锁消息
Quite a bit of cash to make it all go away.
更精彩的在后面呢  我和坎迪丝·弗德
Oh, it gets better. I was talking to Candace Ford
及其他几个女孩交谈时
and a couple of the other girls.
大家都称鲍比·斯塔克
They said that Bobby Stark had started paying
对安波儿相当关注
quite a lot of attention to Amber.
可能关注过头了吧
Maybe it was unwanted attention.
也许鲍比不懂拒绝是什么意思
Maybe Bobby didn't know how to take no for an answer.
你在看我吗
you lookin' at me? Hmm?
-你在看我吗  -斯塔克先生  我是探长
- You lookin' at me? - Mr. Stark, I'm detective--
周围没有别人  你一定是在看我
Nobody else around. You must be lookin' at me.
-斯塔克先生  -嗯
- Mr. Stark. - Hmm?
-请坐  -你觉得刚才那个怎样
- Have a seat, please. - Yeah. Hey, you like that bit?
我在学罗伯特·迪尼洛
That's my, uh, Bobby De Niro.
扮演一个杀人狂
Playing a homicidal maniac.
很像吧
Sold it though, right?
瞧  我还能演反派
See, I got this range as an actor.
这你可能不知道
You probably don't know about that
因为我通常都是以好爸爸的角色形象示人
because I'm always typecast as Mr. Nice-guy dad.
我倒不怀疑你有那本事
Yeah, well, I don't think you'll have that problem
作为谋杀嫌疑人  你装的还挺像
now that you're a murder suspect.
谋杀嫌疑人  什么  你开玩笑吧
Murder suspect? What? Is she joking? You joking?
你跟安波儿·米德伯瑞是什么关系
What was your relationship with Amber Middleberry?
不是吧  你来真的吗  我没有杀她
Oh, come on. Are you serious? I didn't kill her.
要真说有什么  我也就是想招募她
If anything, I was trying to recruit her.
-招她干嘛  -招她来我的女神号列车
- Recruit her? For what? - Yeah, for my, uh, Goddess Train.
-女神号列车  -我的一个小型选美节目
-The Goddess Train? - It's my own little private pageant.
安波儿是如何答复这个诱人不已的邀请的
And how did Amber respond to this oh-so-enticing offer?
坦白说  她还没想通  但已经快了
You know what? She hadn't seen the light yet, but she was coming around.
我一眼就能发现谁大有星途
I could always tell the innocent act when I see it.
再说了 谁不想借我鲍比一举成名
Besides, who wouldn't want to ride the Bobby rocket?
据我们所知谁都不想
Everyone from what we hear.
斯塔克先生  我觉得是这么回事
Mr. Stark, here's what I think happened--
晚餐后  你叫安波儿去了你的更衣室
After dinner, you invited Amber back to your dressing room,
她拒绝了你的提议
and she had the bad sense to agree.
因此你想用别的办法
And that's when you tried to make another pitch
-逼她就范  -但她坚决不从
- to get her on board your Goddess Train. - When she shot you down,
于是你恼羞成怒扼死了她
you flew into a rage and you strangled her.
你在那个舞台上彩排了一整周
You were rehearsing on that stage all week.
-了解所有设备  -打住
-You knew all of the equipment-- - just stop.
你先打住好吗
Would you just--just stop?
不觉得你们疯了吗
You guys are crazy, you know that?
那也许你能解释一下
Okay, well, then maybe you can explain
为什么你外套上掉下的这个小亮片
why we found this broken sequin from your jacket
会在她身上呢
on her body.
昨晚11点到凌晨1点你在哪里
Where were you between 11:00 and 1:00 a.m. last night?
我不知道
Uh... I don't know.
说真的我印象很模糊
I'm a little foggy on that, actually.
-我玩得太厉害  -跟谁一起
-I was, uh, partying pretty hard. - Who were you with?
我不太清楚  但是
I'm not sure, but...
不管是谁  我们当时肯定用了草莓油
whoever it was, we were definitely using strawberry oil.
那说白了
Okay, so let me get this straight.
你昨晚既不知道自己在哪儿
You don't remember where you were
也不知道自己在干嘛是吧
or what you were doing last night?
这很糟糕  是吧
That's bad, right?
那家伙吞的药丸够开个药店了
That guy's dropped more pills than a 3-fingered pharmacist.
我实在无法相信一个在电视上
I just can't believe that someone who's given
扮演慈父的人会杀人
so much great fatherly advice on TV could be guilty of murder.
他是个嗑药上瘾的色狼
Well, he's a drug-addled predator
还不小心在尸体上留下了证据
Who left physical evidence on the body.
好吧  你非要这么说...
Well, when you put it that way...
-埃斯波西托  -在
- Hey, Esposito. - Yo.
我们要查一下斯塔克那晚的行踪
We need to reconstruct Stark's evening.
查下他的通话记录  仔细查查酒店的监控录像
Check his phone records, double-check security cameras at the hotel.
我们需要确切证据  证明他出现在犯罪现场
We need hard evidence to place him at the crime scene.
我找到点东西可能有所帮助
I got something that might help.
安波儿吃晚餐时带着她的小提琴
Amber had her violin with her at dinner,
但在她尸体边和
But it wasn't with the body
-案发现场任何地方都没有  -那小提琴去哪儿了
- or anywhere at the crime scene. - So where'd it go?
安波儿去过酒店
Well, we know Amber went to the hotel,
她可能放在房里了
so maybe she dropped it off there.
但警察搜过酒店房间  不在那儿
Except uniforms inventoried the room. It wasn't there,
她父亲和顾问也没见到
and her dad and consultant didn't see it either.
那也许她被杀的时候还带着它
So maybe she had it when she was killed.
后来被鲍比·斯塔克处理掉了
And Bobby Stark disposed of it.
查查酒店附近的垃圾桶  垃圾车  下水道
Check trash cans, dumpsters, and sewer drains by the hotel.
如果有人见到他丢弃小提琴
If someone saw him ditch the violin,
-我们就能将他与谋杀联系起来  -这就去
- we can connect him to the murder. - Right on.
选美盛会的勾心斗角
Oh, beauty pageant intrigue.
司空见惯的故事了
Some things never change. Ah!
噢  找到了
Oh, here it is.
-我不知道你参加过  -那是因为我没胜出
- I didn't know you competed. - Well, that's because I didn't win.
但我告诉你  我们那时的竞争
Oh. But I will tell you, the women I competed against--
-跟现在的一样激烈  -你的才艺是什么
- Just as cutthroat as they are now. - What was your talent?
我穿套头衫的方式
The way I wore a sweater.
-亲爱的  -阿丽克西斯
- Hi, honey. - Hey, Alexis.
怎么了
What's wrong?
阿什利做了决定
Ashley made his decision.
不妙
Uh-oh.
斯坦福吗
Stanford?
不是
No.
他决定在纽约上大学
He decided to go to school here in New York.
那有什么不好吗
What's not good about that?
斯坦福是他的梦想
Stanford was his dream.
我不想成为他的绊脚石
I don't want to stand in the way of that.
他将来会恨我的
He'll just end up hating me for it.
这将是他人生最重要的决定
And this could be the most important decision of his life,
所以我也做了个决定
So I made a decision, too.
我跟他分手了
I broke up with him.
宝贝
Oh, baby.
会没事的
No, it's okay.
她是对的
well, she's right, you know?
高中恋爱十有八九没结果
I mean, odds are, it won't work out.
-她只是很实际  -谈恋爱不是做数学题
- She's just being practical. - Relationships aren't math problems.
不能靠实际来解决问题
You don't solve them by being practical.
万一她遇到的是真爱呢
I mean, what happens when she meets her soul mate,
因为不够实际  就放弃努力争取吗
but she doesn't risk it because it's not practical?
夏威夷旅行怎么样  耳环呢
Okay, then what about Hawaii? Earrings?
内衣呢
Ooh. Lingerie?
肯定是给女人送礼物
Things you buy a woman.
猜猜游戏我最会了
I used to kill on "Pyramid."
是我结婚30周年纪念
It's my 30th anniversary.
恭喜  长官
Oh, Sir, congratulations.
结婚30年了  你还不知道该送她什么吗
30 years of marriage, and you don't know what to buy her?
如果你结婚的时间足够长  就会知道
If you stayed married long enough, you'd know,
十年纪念日过去后就想不出什么新招了
it's hard to stay original after the first ten.
-说的也是  -那你的婚姻成功秘诀是什么
- That's fair. - So what's the secret to your success?
没什么秘诀  只是
There's no secret. Just...
经常见面
keep showing up.
关于鲍比·斯塔克有什么收获吗
Any luck on Bobby Stark?
有  但你可能不会喜欢
Yeah, but you're not gonna like it.
狗仔队拍到他进入翠贝卡大酒店时的照片
Paparazzi snapped photos of him going into the Tribeca Grand Hotel
时间是11点半  而且是和一个戴墨镜的褐发美人一起
11:30 with a brunette wearing jackie o. glasses.
凌晨1点  他离开了酒店  紧接着
1:00 a.m., he left, at which point
又到一个男士酒吧看摔跤
he relocated to a gentlemen's club to watch mud wrestling.
安波儿离开房间时是11点
Amber left her room at 11:00.
11点到11点半之间他在哪儿
Where was he between 11:00 and 11:30?
在去翠贝卡酒店的出租车上
In a cab on his way to Tribeca.
确定吗
And we know this for a fact?
是的  他一路都在微博上发自己扮酷的照片
Yeah, he was tweeting photos of his manhood along the way.
微博就要这样才有人气嘛
And that's how you trend on twitter.
那么安波儿身上那块亮片就是
So the sequin must have broken off
他碰到她时落下的
onto Amber after he bumped up against her.
-放他走  他不是凶手  -好的
-Cut him loose. He's not our guy. - Right.
-这意味着线索又断了  -我可不这么想
- Which means we are dead in the water. - I wouldn't go that far.
她失窃的小提琴  我们找到了
Her stolen violin? We found it.
-在哪  -被丢在酒店后面的垃圾箱里
- Where? - Dumped in a garbage bin behind the hotel.
被凶手处理了
Disposed of by our killer,
-但不是原先以为的那个凶手  -有指纹吗
- just not the killer we thought. - Did we get prints?
是的  有安波儿·米德伯瑞的
Yeah, Amber Middleberry's
还有另一组指纹属于我们可爱的
and one other set belonging to the lovely,
才华横溢的
the talented...
来自佐治亚州的选手
contestant from Georgia.
也就是...  噢
Which one was... oh.
安波儿跟我从"小闪星"选美赛起就是好朋友了
Amber and I have been friends since Little Miss Spangles.
你们怎么会认为是我杀了她
Why would you think I killed her?
因为小提琴盒上到处是你的指纹  乔伊
Because your prints were all over the violin case, Joy.
而昨天晚宴结束离开时  她还随身带着
And she had it with her when she came back from dinner last night.
她整理紧身衣时我帮她拿着的
I held it for her while she fixed her tights.
紧身衣也被扔在小提琴上呢
They were on the violin, too.
她本不可能进入半决赛的
She wasn't even supposed to be a semifinalist,
但她搞定了所有的问答题
but then she nailed all her pageant questions.
那本应是她的弱点
It was supposed to be her weakness,
但她让所有人都震撼了  她胜利在望
but she blew everyone away. She was going to win.
于是你杀了她之后  丢掉了她的小提琴
So then you killed her and you dumped her violin.
不  不是这样的
No, that is not what happened.
昨晚我们回酒店时
Last night when we went back to the hotel,
我看见她回到房间  放下东西后又出去了
I saw her go into her room, drop off her stuff, and then leave again.
但她走得很匆忙  房门没关好
But she left so fast, her door didn't close all the way,
于是我去替她关门  不经意看见了她的小提琴
so I went to shut it, and that's when I saw her violin.
她将它留在那里  像是在示威一样
She just left it there. It was like a sign.
我心想
I thought...
乔伊·琼斯  你有多想赢
Joy Jones, how badly do you want this?
你有多想赢
How badly did you want it?
不惜一切
More than anything.
我25岁了
I'm 25.
我快超龄了
I'm old.
这是我最后一年能参加比赛
This is the last year I can qualify.
我想要是我丢掉她的小提琴
I thought if I took her violin,
或许会让她大受打击
it might throw her off enough
在才艺决赛时我就能打败她了
in the talent finals that I could beat her.
但那还不够  是吧  你心想
But that wasn't enough for you, was it? You thought,
为何不将安波儿彻底踢出比赛呢
why not just take Amber out of the contest completely?
不  我只拿了她的小提琴
No. All I did was take her violin,
当我得知她死后  我慌了
and when I found out she was dead, I panicked.
我怕会被人发现  于是将它丢了
I thought someone might find out, so I threw it away.
演技不错  乔伊
That is pretty good act, Joy.
但法官是不会相信的
But the judges just aren't buying it.
不  我发誓
No, I swear.
我不需要杀了安波儿来将她踢出比赛
I didn't have to kill Amber to get her out of the pageant.
我在她的小提琴盒里发现了些东西
I found something in her violin case,
一些可怕的东西
something awful.
你发现了什么
And what did you find?
她遭杀害的原因
The reason she was murdered.
要是这传出去了  会毁了她的
If these got out, it would've ruined her.
她会被永远踢出这个圈子的
She would've been kicked off the circuit for good.
噢  我的天
Oh, my god.
-她完全...  -一丝不挂
- She is absolutely, totally... - Naked.
照片背后有条留言
There's a note on the back of that one.
"你知道代价是什么  不乖乖付钱  我就毁了你"
"You know my price. Pay up or I will destroy you."
她被勒索了
So she was being blackmailed.
看来某人将恐吓付诸实施了
Looks like somebody made good on their threat.
选美皇后们和裸照
Beauty queens and naked pictures--
就像美国的社交名流和性爱录像
as american as socialites and sex tapes.
安波儿渴望赢得这场选美比赛
Amber dreamt of winning this pageant,
她怎么会拍那样的照片
why would she take those photos?
我是说  她明白那样做有多冒险
I mean, she knew the chance that she was taking.
拥有智慧和美貌并不代表
Well, just because you're smart and beautiful
你有好的判断力
doesn't mean you have good judgment.
我不是在说自己
I didn't mean me.
刚跟安波儿的父亲联络完
Just got off with Amber's father.
对话很艰难
That was a tough conversation.
你是说  他不知道照片的事吗
You mean, he didn't know about the photos?
安波儿也没有告诉他关于勒索的事
And Amber didn't tell him about the blackmailer either
或者向他借钱
or try to borrow money.
或者她自己付清了
Well, maybe she paid off the blackmailer on her own.
不可能  安波儿的所有钱
Not an option. Any money Amber did have
都花在了鞋子  长袍和晒黑喷雾上
went to paying for shoes, gowns, and spray tans.
她的账户里只剩下50块钱
She only had 50 bucks in the bank.
而她最近也没有去提款
And she didn't have any recent withdrawals either.
贾斯汀说她心烦意乱  或者是因为
Justin said that she was upset. Maybe that's because
她没有足够的钱付给勒索者
she didn't have the money to make it go away.
那么为何要杀了她
Yeah, but then why kill her?
我是说  有脑子的勒索者
I mean, a smart blackmailer
都会给她点时间去筹钱
would give her the time to get the cash.
除非她威胁去报警
Not if she threatened to go to the police,
逼得他采取致命行动
forcing him to take deadly action.
致命行动  这标题不错
Deadly action-- that's a good title.
我重新查过了她的电话
I rechecked her phone.
没有任何奇怪的通话记录
There's no record of any unusual calls.
我想勒索者是通过酒店的电话联络她
I figure the blackmailer contacted her through her hotel phone,
那样就反查不到他身上了
that way he couldn't be traced.
卡塞尔  你看过这些照片了吗
Castle, have you taken a look at these photos?
只看了跟调查有关的部分
Only in so far as it pertains to the investigation.
看看这打光和构图
Look at the lighting and the composition.
拍照的人很懂摄影技术
Whoever took these knew something about photography.
-一个专业摄影师  -这事经常发生
- A professional. - I mean, it happens all the time.
模特和专业摄影师拍照  拍完后
Girl gets a session with a pro, they finish, he offers
摄影师提出拍一些艺术照  模特急于用钱
to take a few art shots, she's desperate for the cash,
摄影师承诺照片永远不会曝光
he promises he'll never show it to anybody...
某一天模特成名了  这时候
Until she makes it big, in which case,
-照片突然出现了  -埃斯波西托
- they suddenly surface. - Esposito,
找选美顾问问话
let's get ahold of the pageant consultant.
还有将和安波儿合作过的
Let's get a list of all the photographers
摄影师全都列出来
that Amber's had sessions with.
-其中一人可能就是勒索者  -好的
- One of them might be our blackmailer. - All right.
这或许就是她心烦的原因
This must have been what she was so upset about.
她清楚如果选美大会发现了
She knew, if the pageant found out,
一切就都完了
it would've all been over.
全完了  但她为什么不告诉我
It is all over. But why didn't she just tell me?
你有头绪这些照片是谁拍的吗
Do you have any idea who might have taken these photographs?
看这发型  应该是六个月前了
With that hairstyle, it must have been six months ago.
我要查一下我的行程表
I'll have to check my calendar.
警员们问过了
So uniforms talked
跟安波儿亲近的选美参赛者
to the pageant girls that Amber was closest to.
她没有跟任何人说照片的事
She didn't tell them about the photos either.
她大概认为这事会被别人利用  反咬她一口
Well, she probably thought they'd use it against her.
贝克特  你是女人  对吧
Beckett, you're a woman, right?
长官  我不知道该送什么礼物给你老婆
Sir, I have no idea what to get your wife.
还没想好要送什么吗
Still no luck on the gift?
想破头也没头绪
Keep coming up empty.
给女人最好的礼物
The best thing to give a woman
就是她不经意说出口想要
is something she said she wanted
却又觉得你根本不会放心上的东西
When she didn't think you were listening.
要是我真的没放心上呢
What if I wasn't listening?
礼卷怎么样
Gift certificate?
根据她的选美顾问说
So according to her pageant consultant,
安波儿六个月前进城拍过照
Amber was in the city about six months ago for a photo shoot.
他认为跟那些照片的拍摄时间相近
He thinks they were taken around the same time.
谁是摄影师
And who was the shoot with?
一个叫戴克斯·拉蒂莫的摄影师
A photographer named Dax Lattimer.
他有前科吗
Does he have a record?
没有  但我打听过了
Negative, but I asked around,
这家伙是拍裸照的老手了
and the guy's no stranger to dirty pictures.
除了拍摄肖像照
On top of headshots,
他还兼职为成人杂志拍照
he also freelances for adult magazines.
看上去像是我们要找的人  他现在在哪
Well, sounds like our guy. Where is he now?
他在曼哈顿东村区的工作室
He's at a studio in the East Village.
-我现在就过去  -好的  我让莱恩跟你碰头
- I'm heading there now. - Okay. I'll have ryan meet you.
当然  我记得安波儿  是个甜心
Sure, I remember Amber. Very sweet gal.
我为她拍了些肖像照
I took some headshots for her.
你当时还拍了其他照片吗
You take anything else while you were at it?
比如她的裸照呢
Maybe some snaps of her wearing nothing but a smile?
安波儿不是那类的女孩  她光彩照人
Amber wasn't the type. She was all about the glamour.
到底怎么回事
So what's this about?
她被谋杀了
she was murdered.
我们认为凶手
And we think whoever killed her
就是拍这张照片的人
took this picture right here.
不是我拍的  我没有那么平庸
Yeah, well, I didn't take this. I'm not that mediocre.
真的吗  这些照片是在
Really? These were shot around
你跟安波儿合作时期照的
the time you worked with Amber.
而且我们都知道你不止拍宠物和全家福
And we all know you do more than just pets and families.
嘿  混口饭吃都不容易
Hey, we all have to pay the bills.
而安波儿作为冉冉升起的新星
And with Amber's star on the rise,
这张照片定然价值不菲
that photo's worth some serious coin.
像她那样漂亮的女孩
Pretty girl like that,
跟你独处一室
alone here with you in the studio?
你要相信我  这张照片不是我拍的
Hey, you have to believe me. I didn't take this photograph.
再说了  我们不是孤男寡女
Besides, we weren't alone.
她和其他人一起
She was with someone.
-谁  -貌似是男朋友
- Who? - Some boyfriend.
那家伙是个怪胎
The guy was a real creep, too.
安波儿没有男朋友
Amber didn't have a boyfriend.
她在这里的时候有
Well, she did when she was here.
实际上  他还把自己幻想成摄影师
In fact, he fancied himself a photographer,
一直告诉我要在自然光下对她进行拍摄
kept telling me I should shoot Amber in natural light.
这个男朋友叫什么
This boyfriend have a name?
杰瑞  杰瑞米什么的
Jerry. Jeremy. Something like that.
拉蒂莫先生  昨天晚上十一点
Mr. Lattimer, where were you night before last
到凌晨一点这期间你在哪里
between 11:00 p.m. and 1:00 a.m.?
在家和我老婆在一起
At home with my wife,
哄我得了疝气的儿子睡觉
trying to rock my colicky son to sleep.
楼里面有门卫  你们可以去核实
It's a doorman building, so you can check.
好的  多谢
Okay, thanks.
安波儿的爸爸说她曾经有个男朋友
Amber's dad said that she used to have a boyfriend--
名叫杰瑞米·凯佩尔
Jeremy Keiper.
凯佩尔  他是不是怪里怪气的
Keiper? Was he creepy?
是的  她爸爸是这么认为的
Yeah, well, her dad thought so.
据他所知  他们去年年底分手了
As far as he knows, they broke up late last year
因为她意识到他在拖她的后腿
because she realized that he was holding her back.
爸爸觉得男朋友还在伊利诺斯州
The dad thinks that the boyfriend's still in Illinois.
这就是敲诈的绝妙之处
Well, that's the beauty of blackmail--
它不受地点的限制
You can do it from anywhere.
敲诈  或许是  但谋杀  绝对不是
Blackmail, maybe. But not murder.
我们何不去查查凯佩尔最近是否拜访过她
Why don't we find out if Keiper paid her a visit lately?
马上去办
On it.
蹩脚男友配选美皇后
Bad boyfriends and pageant queens?
这简直是黛比·文妮科故事的翻版
This is like Debbie Winokur all over again.
你又忆起往昔了
You having flashbacks?
那简直就是我独自一人深陷越南
It was my own private Vietnam.
我们家里闻起来都是发胶
Our place smelled of hair spray,
香水和香烟的味道
perfume, and cigarettes.
我都惊讶于我们怎么没把自己烧着
I'm surprised that we didn't spontaneously combust.
我爱死早上发胶的味道了
I love the smell of hair spray in the morning.
闻起来像是
It smells like...
胜利
victory.
打扰一下  卡塞尔先生
Excuse me, Mr. Castle?
阿什利
Ashley.
我很抱歉在您工作的时候打扰您
I'm sorry to bug you at work,
但是阿里克西斯定了个不打电话不联系的政策
but Alexis established a-a no calls, no contact policy.
她告诉我了
She told me.
我犯了个大错
Look, I-I made a big mistake.
我觉得如果我选择了斯坦福
I thought if I chose Stanford,
阿里克西斯就会觉得我把她甩掉了
Alexis would think that I was blowing her off.
但是相反  她生气是因为我选择了她
Instead, she's mad at me because I chose her
而不是我想要去的学校
over where I want to go to school.
现在我要去斯坦福了
So now I'm going to Stanford,
那是我最想去的学校  但是
which is where I wanted to go in the first place, but--
但如果你打电话告诉她
But if you call her and tell her that,
她就会对你更生气
she'll be even angrier with you
因为你忽略了她的界限
for ignoring her boundaries.
完全正确  我觉得阿里克西斯和我
Exactly. Look, I think alexis and I
能够让这段异地恋走下去
can make the whole long-distance thing work.
我真的这么觉得  您能转告她吗
I really do. Would you tell her that?
您能帮我和她谈谈吗
Would you talk to her for me?
阿什利  我很感激
Ashley, I-I appreciate,
今天你能找我来谈话
it was probably very hard for you to come down
对你来说一定很难
and talk to me today,
但是我觉得由我来不太合适...
but I just don't think it's very appropriate for me to get--
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle,
您有没有对一个执意推开您的人
have you ever been crazy about someone
痴心不改
who was determined to push you away?
卡塞尔  哦  对不起
Hey, Castle, uh-- oh, sorry, guys.
不...
No, it...
没事
It's o--um...
阿什利  我很抱歉  我得走了
Ashley, I'm--I'm sorry. I do have to go.
请您考虑一下  好吗
Please just, um, think about it, okay?
好的
Okay.
找你干什么
What's that about?
他想让我帮他求情
He wants me to advocate for him.
真可爱
Oh. That's sweet.
-是啊  -还很尴尬
- Yeah. - And awkward.
尴尬多过可爱
Mostly awkward.
贝克特  我刚和杰瑞米·凯佩尔的妈妈通了电话
Yo, Beckett! I just got off the phone with Jeremy Keiper's mom.
发现上个月杰瑞米就搬到了纽约
Turns out Jeremy moved to New York last month,
说他要"改头换面"
said he was going to "make something of himself."
看起来他把自己改成了敲诈者和杀人犯
Looks like he made himself into a blackmailer and a killer.
杰瑞米·凯佩尔  纽约警局  开门
Jeremy Keiper, NYPD. Open up.
凯佩尔先生
Mr. Keiper?
有人吗
Anybody here?
看起来有人对旧情难以放手啊
Looks like someone had a hard time letting go.
卡塞尔
Castle.
就简直就是个经典的谋杀后自杀
This is a classic murder-suicide.
杰瑞米敲诈他的前女友
Jeremy blackmails his ex-girlfriend,
并不是因为他需要钱
not because he needs the money,
而是因为他对她念念不忘
but because clearly, he's obsessed with her.
安波儿拒绝了他和他的勒索
Amber rejects him and his scheme-y schemes.
他就发疯崩溃  把她杀了  之后
He flips, he snaps, he kills her, and then,
面对自己的所作所为  把自己吊死了
faced with the reality of what he's done, hangs himself.
你的理论有一个漏洞  卡塞尔
Only one problem with your theory, Castle.
-是什么  -这不是自杀
- Which is? - This wasn't a suicide.
不是吗
This wasn't?
如果他是自行上吊
If he'd hanged himself,
他脖子上的勒痕角度应向上
the marks on his neck would angle upwards.
是啊  就是向上的
Yes, which they do.
是啊  但如果他是被人勒死的
Yes, but if he was strangled,
勒痕应该是水平的  两种痕迹均出现在脖子上
the marks would go straight across. This guy's got both.
把他吊起来只是为了掩饰他是被人勒死的
Then the hanging was a cover up for the strangulation.
而且在手臂和肋骨周围有死前瘀伤
Well, there's also peri-mortem bruising on the arms and across the ribs.
我想死前一定有挣扎
I'm guessing there was a struggle.
估算的死亡时间
Estimated time of death?
从尸温和尸斑判断
Well, judging by temperature and lividity,
他早于安波儿·米德伯瑞半天遇害
He was killed half a day before Amber Middleberry.
早于安波儿
Before Amber?
是的  早
Yes, before!
现在你能动动吗  你挡住我的光了
Now can you please move? You're in my light.
这完全没道理啊   如果他没有杀安波儿
This doesn't make any sense. If he didn't kill Amber...
勒索者和被勒索的人怎么都死翘翘了
How do a blackmailer and his victim both end up dead?
看看这个
Yo, check this out.
他的硬盘内容被消除了
His hard drive's been wiped.
这就是我们的联系  卡塞尔
That's our connection, Castle.
安波儿和杰瑞米的相同之处就是
It's the one thing that Amber and Jeremy had in common--
那些照片
those photos.
有人不想让它们曝光
Someone didn't want them to see the light of day.
安波儿的爸爸根本就不知道有这事
Amber's dad had no idea this was going on with his daughter.
在过去的半年里她都没有提过
She didn't even mention Jeremy's name
杰瑞米的名字
in the last six months.
在他们在一起的时候
Is there anything else that Jeremy and Amber
没有卷入到其他事情里面吗
could've been involved with while they were together?
没有  他是没想起来什么
No, not that he can recall.
这些照片  以当今的标准来看
These pictures, by today's standards,
可以说是很有品位
are--are downright tasteful.
这种照片怎么会导致人被害呢
How do these get you killed?
可能与艳照无关
It can't be about naked pictures.
-一定是发生了其他事情  -除非
- Something else must have been going on. - Unless...
-除非什么  -除非杰瑞米不是唯一的勒索者
- Unless what? - Unless Jeremy wasn't the only blackmailer.
如果他有个同伙呢  我是说
What if he had a partner? I mean,
我们知道安波儿在被害当晚与人发生了争吵
we know Amber was arguing with someone the night she was killed.
我们也知道这个人不可能是杰瑞米
We know it couldn't have been Jeremy,
因为他已经死了
because he was already dead.
为什么杰瑞米的同伙把他杀了呢
Why would the partner kill Jeremy?
也许他们闹翻了
Maybe they had a falling out.
也许杰瑞米决定他不能伤害安波儿
Maybe Jeremy decided he couldn't hurt amber,
但是同伙还是想要他的钱
but the partner still wanted his payday.
所以他就杀掉杰瑞米决定自己去找安波儿
So he takes out Jeremy and decides to go after Amber himself?
但安波儿说他是在虚张声势
But Amber decides to call his bluff.
她说她会联系警方
She says she's gonna contact the police.
于是勒索者就别无选择  他只能杀掉她
Now the blackmailer has no choice. He has to kill her
然后销毁所有勒索的证据
and get rid of all the evidence of blackmail.
莱恩
Ryan.
把所有关于杰瑞米·凯佩尔的资料都给我
Give me everything you got on Jeremy Keiper.
对不起  宝贝
I'm sorry, baby.
很晚了  这里就交给你了
Whoa. It's late. I'll leave you to it.
看什么呢
Whatcha looking at?
你真的很想他  是不是
You really miss him, don't ya?
你知道  我不喜欢去干预
You know I-I hate to interfere--
从什么时候开始的
Since when?
有道理
Point taken.
阿什利今天来分局找我了
Ashley dropped by the precinct to see me today.
是吗  为什么
He did? Why?
他想让我帮他说情
He wanted me to intercede on his behalf.
他说了什么
What'd he say?
他看起来比你快乐不到哪去
Well, he looked about as happy as you do,
他想让我告诉你
and he wanted me to tell you
他决定去斯坦福
that he has decided to go to Stanford.
还有
And...
他想要给长距离恋爱一次机会
he wants to give a long-distance relationship a shot.
他认为这能成功
He thinks it could work.
你怎么想的
What do you think?
我认为没有绝对的事情
I think that nothing is certain.
还有你可能在放弃一件
And you could be ending something
如果你再给点时间
that might have worked if you had just...
说不定会成功的事情
given it a little more time.
如果我只是在避免
What if I'm just cutting my losses on
一件注定会失败的事情呢
something that was never meant to be?
那么  我们可以成为
Well, then we can be the father-daughter version of
父女版的《灰色花园》
"Grey Gardens."
人生就像一段旅程
Life is a journey,
我们无法预测要发生的事
and there is no predicting the outcome.
你唯一能掌握的就是你的选择  而...
The only thing you can control are your choices, and they'll...
这些选择会决定你的成长你的未来
They'll define who you are.
我只是不想看到你
I would just hate to see you
专注于眼前的问题
so focused on the problem right in front of you
致使你...错过充满可能性的一切
that you... completely miss the entire picture.
真是不错的建议
That's pretty good advice.
是啊  真是不错  是吧
Yeah. Yeah, actually it is, isn't it?
是啊
Yeah.
记得提醒我圣诞节帮你订一刊女性杂志
Remind me to get you a subscription to a girlie magazine for Christmas.
你考虑的真周到
Oh, that is so thoughtful,
但我不是在看裸女
but I'm not looking at the naked girl.
那你在看什么
What are you looking at?
除了裸女之外的一切
Everything but the naked girl.
我们把注意力都放在安波儿身上
We were so focused on Amber,
我们差点忘记了其他的一切
we almost missed the entire picture.
如果安波儿和杰瑞米被杀不是因为
What if Amber and Jeremy were killed not because of
照片中的人  而是因为拍照的地点呢
who was in this photo, but because of where the photo was taken?
看上去眼熟吗
Anything look familiar?
当然
Sure does.
你可以等会儿再谢我
You can thank me later.
说到杀人动机
Talk about a motive for murder.
如果这些照片被登上小报
If these photos got out to the tabloids...
肯定会毁了一切的
It would destroy everything.
-纽约警局  -他们在里面
- NYPD. - They're inside.
安波儿的追悼会应该办的简单又不失品位
The memorial for Amber should be simple, tasteful...
-还要非常的典雅  -是的
- And very, very classy. - Yes.
探长
Detective.
有什么需要我帮忙的吗
Is there something I can help you with?
是的  我们需要问几个问题
Yes, we need to ask you a few questions.
问吧
Ask away.
好的
Fine.
告诉我们安波儿·米德伯瑞
Tell us about the blackmail and the murder
被敲诈和谋杀的实情
of Amber Middleberry.
关掉摄像机  出去
Shut the cameras off. Go, now!
我以为你说所有人都喜欢看花絮
I thought you said that everybody loves the underbelly.
这是怎么回事  维克多
This... what's going on, Victor?
事实上我们终于发现了
What's going on is, we finally figured out who,
除了安波儿
aside from Amber...
还有谁会因为这些照片而紧张
would be nervous about these photos.
什么照片
What photos?
我的天  我的天呐  维克多
Oh, my god. Oh, my god! Victor.
-我的天  -不是看上去的那样
- Oh, my god! - I... it's not what it looks like.
不是看上去的那样  这是
It's not what it looks like? This is...
这是我们在汉普顿的房子
This is our house in the Hamptons.
-这是我们的床  -这是我们度假用床
- This is our bed. - It's our vacation bed.
就在你在拍卖会上买的
Right underneath the $2 million Picard
那幅价值两百万的皮卡尔画下面
that you purchased at the auction,
也正是和挂在
which just happens to be the companion
你办公室的这幅是一对
to this painting here in your office.
《现代建筑》中他们为你写的文章
We read all about it on the spread
让我们知晓了一切
they did on you in "Today's Architect."
看上去你因为这幅皮卡尔而地位提升不少
Looks as though you were hoisted on your own Picard.
-我可以解释  -维克多  我们说好的
- I can explain. - We agreed, Victor. Never again.
那只是个周末
It was just a weekend.
只是个周末  我在汉普顿还有朋友
Just a weekend? I have friends in the Hamptons.
要是有人看到了怎么办
What if somebody saw?
我会因为你管不好
I won't be humiliated
自己的小弟弟而丢尽脸面的
because you can't keep it in your pants!
-没人看到  -没人看到
- No one saw. - No one saw.
不  你拍了照好让所有人都能看到
No, you took photos so everyone could see.
那些照片不是我拍的
I didn't take those pictures.
我是这么想的  安波儿被敲诈了
Here's what I think happened... Amber was being blackmailed.
她支付不了  所以她找到你帮忙
She couldn't pay, so she came to you for help.
但是你为了大局着想  这些照片
Only you had a lot to lose, and those pictures,
终究是会传出去的
they have a way of getting out.
于是你没有付敲诈者钱  而是杀了他
So instead of paying off her blackmailer, you killed him,
然后你回到这里把她解决了
and then you came back here to take care of her.
不是这样的
That's not what happened.
已经没有摄像机在拍了  拜伦先生
The cameras aren't rolling any longer, Mr. Baron.
你不用再演戏了
You can drop the act.
我不是在演戏  安波儿没有被敲诈
It's not an act. Amber wasn't being blackmailed.
那个狡猾的婊子在敲诈我
The conniving bitch was blackmailing me.
她在敲诈你
She was blackmailing you?
她给我看了那些照片
She showed me the pictures.
她告诉我  她叫她男朋友
She told me that she had her boyfriend come
趁我不在时过来拍的
and take 'em while I was away.
等等  你把她一个人留在我的房子里
Wait. You left her alone in my house?
我当时要到市里开会  我马上就回去了
I had a meeting in the city. I was coming right back.
你怎么能这么笨呢  维克多
How could you be so stupid, Victor?
她说如果我帮她赢得选美比赛
She said if helped her win the pageant,
这些照片就不会被公开
the photos would never see the light of day.
你知道代价是什么  不付钱的话我就毁了你
"You know the price. Pay up or I'll destroy you."
这不是写给安波儿的  而是安波儿写的
It wasn't to Amber. It was from amber.
她还和她的男朋友在一起
She was still with her boyfriend.
他们两个人合谋
They were in it together.
那你做了什么
So then what did you do?
我偷偷把选美的问题给了她
I slipped her the pageant questions.
要不然她怎么会答得那么好
Why do you think she was doing so well?
你个混蛋
You ass!
拜伦先生  案发那天晚上
Mr. Baron, where were you
11点到凌晨1点你在哪里
between 11:00 and 1:00 a.m. the night of the murder?
招待会结束后
After the reception,
我和市议员博林杰一起喝了点酒
I had drinks with councilman Bollinger.
我大概凌晨一点到的家
Uh, I got home at, uh, at 1:00 a.m.
凯拉和我在一起  是吧  宝贝
Kayla was with me, weren't you, babe?
凯拉  是真的吗  你和他在一起吗
Kayla, is this true? Were you with him?
是的
Yes.
还有谁知道  维克多
Who else knew, Victor?
我还要在谁面前丢脸
Who do I need to be ashamed in front of?
没有人知道了
No one else knew.
肯定还有人知道
Well, someone else must've,
要不然这两个人就不会死了
otherwise two people wouldn't be dead.
我只告诉了坎迪丝一个人
The only other person I told was Candace.
我告诉了她安波儿的企图
I told her what amber was trying to do...
勒索我  在比赛中作弊
to me, to the pageant.
我让她帮我解决
I told her to take care of it,
让她把问题解决掉
to make the problem go away.
也许她这么做了
Maybe she did.
我不想在这些玻璃杯上看到一点指纹
I don't want to see any fingerprints on those glasses.
对指纹还挺小心的嘛  坎迪丝
Being careful of fingerprints, are we, Candace?
我们想让一切都很完美
We want everything to be perfect.
这场选美真是你的心头肉
This pageant really is your baby.
你注意到了  完美的17年
You noticed? 17 flawless years.
那么你会不惜一切代价来保护它
So then you would do anything to protect it.
我们知道拜伦先生把敲诈的事情告诉了你
We know that Mr. Baron told you about the blackmail.
我们还知道他让你来解决这件事
And we know that he asked you to handle it.
杀她  我想杀了拜伦
Kill her? I wanted to kill Baron.
完美的17年  他想把答案给他的小三
17 flawless years, and he wants me to give her the answers
好让她能戴上王冠
so his little fling can wear the crown?
但如果不这么做
But it was either that
那个狐狸精就会毁了一切
or that snake destroys everything.
安波儿被杀的那个晚上你在哪里
Where were you the night that Amber was killed?
求你别
Please don't.
-弗德女士  -我和别人在一起
- Ms. Ford  - I was with someone.
谁
Who?
我不能说
I can't.
坎迪丝  如果你有不在场证明
Candace, if you have an alibi...
鲍比·斯塔克  我和他一起在翠贝卡酒店
Bobby Stark. I was with him at the Tribeca Grand.
而最糟的是
And the worst part is...
他甚至都不记得了
he doesn't even remember.
翠贝卡酒店确认了谋杀发生的时候
Tribeca grand confirms that Stark was with Candace
斯塔克和坎迪丝在一起
at the time of the murder.
她闻起来是有点草莓精油的味道
She did smell a little bit like strawberry oil.
拜伦的不在场证明也成立
Baron's alibi checks out, too.
我们没有嫌疑犯了
Which leaves us without a suspect.
去跟拜伦的律师交涉
Okay, get into it with Baron's lawyers.
坎迪丝没杀人
Just because Candace didn't kill them
-不代表他没买凶杀人  -好
- doesn't mean he didn't hire someone else to do it. - Right.
盲目而赤裸裸的野心  我想
Blind, naked ambition-- I think
就算黛比·文妮科也会感到厌恶的
even your Debbie Winokur would've been appalled.
她的确会
Yeah, she would've.
黛比想成为选美皇后
Debbie wanted to be a beauty queen
是因为她信仰完美之美
because she believed in the ideals of beauty.
她想达到秀外慧中的境界
She wanted to be beautiful on the inside and outside.
我以为你不喜欢她
I thought you didn't like her.
在她内心深处  在完美妆容和发型下
Well, deep down, behind all of the makeup and the hair,
她也不是一个烂人
She wasn't terrible.
只不过跟她住一起很难熬
She was just a miserable person to live with.
跟安波儿不一样  如果成功意味着作弊
Unlike Amber, winning wouldn't have meant a thing to her
那成功对她而言就一文不值
if she had to cheat to do it.
说起改变你人生的抉择
Yeah, talk about choices that change your life.
你是何时做出那种选择
When do you make that choice?
何时起赢得比赛
When does winning become
-比你的灵魂更重要  -不知道
- more important than your soul? - I don't know.
想要做出安波儿干出来的事
You have to be pretty cold and calculating
得非常冷酷非常精明才行
to make some of the choices Amber did.
冷酷精明
Cold and calculating?
什么
What?
安波儿冷酷又精明
Amber was cold and calculating.
那又怎样
Yeah, so?
这样说来  跟我们聊过她的人里
So all of those people we talked to about her,
有一个在说谎
one of them is lying.
拜伦全美选美赛惨剧发生
Tragedy... struck the Baron's All-American Pageant
一位伊利诺伊洲选手意外而亡
with the untimely passing of our Illinois All-American,
安波儿·米德伯瑞小姐
Ms. Amber Middleberry.
我有幸曾与安波儿亲密共事
I was fortunate to have worked closely with Amber.
她对我而言意味着全世界
She meant the world to me.
那你为什么杀死她
Well, then why did you kill her?
什么  我没杀她
What? I didn't kill Amber.
你在说谎  你一直都在说谎
You're lying. You've been lying to us the whole time.
你跟我们说她心烦意乱  说她感到
You told us that she was upset, that she was feeling
被人占了便宜  受到了威胁
like she was being taken advantage of and threatened.
但她才是威胁别人的人
But she was the one doing the threatening.
她没必要心烦意乱
There was no reason for her to be upset.
你们打断了一次着装排演
You know, you're interrupting a dress rehearsal. Okay?
我都不知道你俩在说什么
I don't even know what you two are talking about.
你完全清楚  你发现了勒索事件
Oh, yes, you do. You got on to the blackmail.
你以为她前男友想
You thought the old boyfriend was taking advantage
占你未来冠军的便宜  所以你找他对质
of your prized client, so you confronted him.
-我们查过你的信用卡  -得知
- We ran your credit cards. - We know
你乘出租车去了杰瑞米的公寓
about the taxi trip you took to Jeremy's apartment.
跟我们说说  你杀害安波儿男朋友时
So tell us, when you killed Amber's boyfriend.
可知道安波儿也参与了这场阴谋
did you know that amber was in on the scheme?
贾斯汀  站住
Justin, stop.
往哪儿跑呢
Where are you going, aah!
给你个建议  贾斯汀
A word of advice, Justin.
女士说站住
When the lady says stop,
那就站住
stop.
贾斯汀坦白了一切
Justin confessed to everything.
他之前三位客户不成气候
His last three clients were losers.
安波儿可使他重返巅峰  要是她输了
Amber was supposed to be his comeback, and if she didn't win,
他就完了
he was through.
显然我们发现的裸照他也发现了
Apparently he found the same naked photos that we did,
却以为她前男友想占她便宜
thought that her ex-boyfriend was trying to exploit her.
他很担心  要是他们报了警
He was worried, if they called the cops,
她的秘密就会曝光  他俩都玩儿完
that her secret would get out, and they'd both be ruined.
所以打算自己解决
So he decided to handle it on his own.
倒霉的是杰瑞米喝醉了
Unfortunately, Jeremy was drunk,
动了手  结果贾斯汀杀了他
He got violent, and Justin ended up killing him.
把他现场布置成自杀
And he staged it like it was a suicide.
安波儿发现后  威胁要告发他
Once Amber found out, she threatened to turn him in,
-他就把她也杀了  -可真是一错连一错
- And he killed her. - That's a whole pageant of bad choices.
你俩干得漂亮
Good work, you two.
-你们都很棒  -谢谢
- Uh, good work, you all. - Thank you.
我看到一位值得授予桂冠的选美皇后
I see a beauty queen worthy of a crown.
你嘴总这么甜  里克
Always the charmer, Rick.
亲爱的  你怎么来了
Baby, what you doin' here?
你明知我会去接你的
You know I was just comin' to swoop you up.
我知道你工作起来
Yeah, well, I know how you lose all sense of time
废寝忘食  所以想直接过来找你
when you're working. I figured I'd meet you here.
你们有什么计划没
Do you guys have any big plans?
跟曼哈顿最佳老公共进晚餐携手舞蹈
Dinner and dancing with the best husband in Manhattan,
早上他送我礼物后  这就变得更加美妙了
especially since he gave me that gift this morning.
你最后送她什么了
Oh, what did you end up giving her?
卡塞尔  我听了你的建议
I followed your advice, Castle.
我想到过去几年
I thought about some of the things
伊芙琳一直在说她想要一样东西
Evelyn said she wanted the past couple of years...
我的礼物就是明年
And my gift to her is, next year,
-我准备退休  -我们要去旅行
- I'm retiring from the force. - We're gonna go traveling.
去很多很浪漫的地方
We're gonna go to all the romantic places.
-等等  真的吗头儿  -你要退休
- Wait. Are-- are you serious, boss? - You really want to retire?
虽然在我的岗位上
I haven't accomplished
我没做到十全十美  但也做的不少了
everything I wanted to on the job, but I've done enough.
我该放手前行了
It's time for me to move on.
史上最佳礼物  更多时间跟罗伊在一起
Best gift ever--more Roy.
我把我的经验
look, I taught you guys everything I know
都传授给你们了
about doing this job, all right?
没有我你们一样会很出色
You're gonna be fine without me.
拜托  别哭丧着脸  请微笑
Oh, for crying out loud, lose the long faces. Smile, please.
这是命令
That's an order.
你们好好照顾自己
Hey, you kids take care, all right?
-老实点  -玩得愉快
- You guys behave now. - You have a good time.
-恭喜两位  晚安  -谢谢
- Congratulations, you guys. Good night. - Thank you.
-拜拜  -结婚纪念日快乐
- Bye. - Happy anniversary.
-晚安队长  -你跟他说什么了
- Good night, Captain. - What the hell did you say to him?
什么也没说  就跟他说
Nothing. No, I just told him
-送他妻子想要的  -该死  卡塞尔
- to listen to what his wife wanted. - Damn, Castle.
你怎么能...我没...
How can you th-- I di--
不可能...
There's no way--
卡塞尔  我还是透漏给你个小秘密吧
Castle, let me let you in on a little secret.
蒙哥马利队长总说要退休
Captain Montgomery retires all the time.
等个一两周
Just give it a week or two.
他就像是纽约警局的布雷特·法夫尔
He's like the Brett Favre of the NYPD.
相信我  他哪儿也不会去
Trust me. He's not going anywhere.
哪也不会去
Not going anywhere.
我正想问你呢
Hey, so I've been meaning to ask you,
阿丽克西斯决定好阿什利的事没
did Alexis make a decision about Ashley?
定了
Oh, she did, actually.
她觉得值得一试
She decided it was, uh, worth the risk.
她会继续和他交往
And she's going to just keep showing up.
好决定
That's a good choice.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
阿什利你在这儿做什么
Ashley, what are you doing here?
-卡塞尔先生  -老爸  你猜怎样
- Hey, Mr. Castle. - Hey, dad. Guess what.
怎样
What?
我要去斯坦福了
I'm going to Stanford.
-什么  -我申请了提前入学
- What? - I'm applying for early admission.
由于我高一开始每学期
And since I've been taking extra classes
都多修学分
each semester since my freshman year,
秋天就能满学分毕业了
I have enough credits to graduate in the fall.
什么
What?
这样我和阿什一月份就能在一起了
Yeah, this way, Ash and I will be together in January,
在大学哟
In college.
什么
What?
先生  这其实是她的主意
That was actually her idea, sir.
什么
What?